all right welcome to today's solution
raising we tried to hold the same one
last week but i
literally came in at nine o'clock no one
was here so i left then both mark and
eric were like what's this happening
today i don't know
anyway today so we're redoing the same
one it's a little ironic daniel's not
here because he's the one who suggested
this one
i know we've had two weeks but we're
doing dating and relationships
so what does that currently look like in
your life
if you're in a significant relationship
or not in a significant relationship we
could always talk about before and that
period of time and then of course what
we would love it to look like
and then what we could do with ten
thousand people and a hundred thousand
dollars
um we'd like to start i'm willing to
start if no one else wants to
all right three seconds of silence i'll
take that as i'm starting
um so dating i don't know i don't date
like
but i have i have dated um i was dating
exclusively men until i figured out i
was queer and now
i'm like it's too complex it's too much
i can't even um
but when i was dating ironically i
really liked craigslist
i really liked putting out into the
world here's what i'm looking for and
whoever
kind of um responded was
kind of perfect now i got a lot of bad
responses as well don't get me wrong
and it didn't it doesn't work for for
women like it doesn't work
looking for a woman it also doesn't
didn't work for men but now it doesn't
work for anyone because they took away
that portion of it but i don't like
online dating i really dislike it i feel
like it's a meat market like it is it's
you're just like yes no no yes yes no
and i'm more complex than that and
everyone else is more complex
and i find one of the reasons i don't
date besides the fact that i'm
kind of here to create game b and i feel
it like i actually i did ayahuasca a few
years ago and
by the only thing i got out of ayahuasca
was that my relationship on this time on
the planet is community community in
general
rather than at one significant other and
um
that seems right to me but i remember my
point if that was
besides that it's complex like for me to
find the person that would be attracted
to me that i'm also attracted to
it's not as easy as going on a first
date like i'd have to go through a
million people you know what i mean
which it's like when you're
heterosexual it's a little easier to
like figure that out
but the more i don't know kinks you have
the more
great sexuality you have the more any of
that the harder it becomes to find
that's going together yet you're still
expected to just go through
just keep going just keep going on dates
just keep finding the one and i'm like i
don't have uh
even now during the pandemic because
what i wanted was online dating actual
online dating like on zoom
because i don't have to go to a coffee
shop where it's sensory overload
and now that everyone's online dating
i'm like maybe after the pandemic i
don't know
we'll see we'll see but that is that is
my share so who would like to share and
everyone's welcome to pass as well if
you don't want to sure
for this portion i can share next um
so i am in a relationship um
i have been together with her for about
three years coming up in
january um so that's kind of where
i'm at but i i'm thinking about
dating in relationships in a
it's it's interesting because the
solution
solution raising and this whole idea
in general is about game b and it's
about
anti-rivalry and omni-win and
solutions to the current paradigm
the current paradigm in a relationship
is like the
ultimate competitive thing
you're competing for a mate and
then when you have them you hold on to
them and you like you're very
you know no one else has this person and
this and that and
and i'm thinking about you know my my
partner and i are experimenting with
open relationships
and so we are kind of in a
place of um seeing
how a primary bond
goes with now these like
kind of extended bonds so um
i don't know what what relationships
will look like in the future but
to me it seems as if especially within a
community
like child raising is more of like a
community aspect in a community
activity than it is meant to be done by
just
a family from like the old times i guess
so kind of going back to the roots there
but i don't know dating how dating can
change um
other than just having more data about
the people
and more like
oh this is your perfect match like i
don't know how
how technology can help
something kind of flourish more
so um yeah
very vague vague statements on that i
don't really have any kind of solid uh
vision for this so you you've both kind
of touched on dating apps haven't you on
on the technology of matching people
with each other and this is
see this is i we've kind of got it all
backwards right
it's symptomatic of the fact that we are
so atomized and we are so
disconnected from each other and our
interactions with each other are so
superficial and so
shallow that we crave the intimacy of
you know a a more profound relationship
and so we go out and we
seek in the marketplace people who might
satisfy some list of requirements that
we come up with that we think is going
to be
a good match for ourselves right and the
whole thing is completely externalized
and
in the head right and not um it's not
just a lived thing
at all right but then what are you gonna
do when all you're having with people is
superficial interactions all day long
every day you know i mean what what what
are you gonna do and so
this is the quandary that we find
ourselves in unable
or untrained should i say in the art of
formation of intimate relationships
while at the same time craving them and
putting all
going all in on this one intimate
relationship we have in our life yeah
finding
the one this whole narrative we have in
our culture of
finding the one and getting married to
them and spending the rest of your life
with them you know what i mean
it's it's a i think all of this [ __ ] is
wrapped up together
in this in in in this loss that we have
experienced at some point in our history
of genuine
intimate relationship with those around
us
um i mean i've no idea what it was like
back in tribal days but i suspect that
you did not get married to and stay with
one person for your whole life i suspect
that the whole
child producing and child rearing thing
was a pretty communal activity i would
imagine i mean as i said i don't know
i'm not an anthropologist i suspect
there was quite a significant variation
from tribe to try to tribe anyway
with these kinds of things um but yeah i
i feel that people don't really know
what they need and they think they do
and they
have this list of stuff they put up on a
dating site it almost never actually
fits because our perception of ourselves
is not
you know you need to just run into
people that somehow fill your gaps right
and then but we are encouraged to go
through this process of creating a
fantasy image of this perfect person and
then every person that we meet
they are measured against this fantasy
and once once we start realizing no
no they're not this fantasy we go off
them right rather than actually just
encountering people as they are meeting
them as they are kind of thing
and the final thing i wanted to say is
just getting but game a-related
um this whole finding a partner getting
married settling down having kids
getting a mortgage getting jobs having
careers
this is all part of the game a treadmill
right and so
i i actually think there is a great deal
of room for the nature of dating and
relationships to change
in the new paradigm because i think the
whole um
substrate in which these things go on
would be profoundly different right and
so the need to find to latch onto this
one person
who's going to satisfy your every need
would be gone because your needs your
emotional needs are being satisfied
in the communal right and finding a
special person that you want to
really get deep with for whatever reason
you know might not be the norm anymore
it might be an occasional thing it might
not be that i mean how many people get
married because they're not really
enough we don't really have that depth
of
thing with each other it's just you know
i'm 28 and if i don't do it soon i'm
never going to get
around to it and it's all this kind of
bollocks right i'll probably talk for
too long i'll stop there sorry
i always like to um listen
because when we started i i wasn't sure
um what what exactly i was going to talk
about because it's such a
wide area and they listened to some of
what uh
julie was saying what jared was saying
and what what eric
just said and okay so for me
personally i i came out of a 35-year
relationship actually it was probably
longer than that
so i was i was married for 35 years
and it ended primarily because
well there were a lot of reasons but i
felt the drive
to do more in in a
bigger community and and she
wanted just a house on the lake right
um and i remember one of the last
conversations we had
i i told her i felt the darkness coming
just
just the polarization i felt it like
almost
in it was like a live thing i could feel
it
i could feel something shifting and uh
and she said do you think your dream is
more important than mine
and they said the darkness will come get
you at the lake anyways it doesn't
matter where you are it's coming for all
of us
but she just saw that as me
going after a dream of mine versus her
so there was a there was a big rift
there i realized there was a rift
um so i i could deny that and and
um as i've done before just kind of
create our little bubble because it was
a nice little bubble
you know the sex was good the intimacy
was good
you know some and that's one of the
things i miss is just the the
intimacy you know the secret touches and
the prolonged hugs and the deep hugs and
things like that
but it it cannot survive when there's
something pulling you one way and
something pulling you the other way
there's there's there's
when there's this big rift it's kind of
like a game a game b
rift is what it felt like now you know
to describe it in terms of
omni wind versus kind of rivalrous
paradigm but i uh
i found that when i came to the game b
facebook group
there was as eric said there's that
feeling of
uh it's almost like intimacy like i've
had some really interesting
conversations
on zoom that felt intimate
you know uh so that's kind of a cool
thing
uh and i think it's possible to feel
that kind of intimacy and that
trust to try and build that now it's
it's when you talk about craigslist it
sounds like they were kind of heading in
the right direction but didn't realize
what they had
and i think um other apps it may be a
possibility i
i would say that there are times
like i've watched uh christopher uh
malapastra i can't remember his name
john verveiki
jordan jordan hall and um guy
seng stock and that was a very
intimate zoom conversation there were
three or four of them
they were very intimate conversations
and there was a
trust there so i i'd say it's
possible and if we could build a
community like that
online then i think
love could love and trust would just
kind of
naturally flow out of that and that
would be a kind of a repurposing
of the technology and that's
anyways that's kind of where i am in in
that trying to move that
from because i realize what eric is
saying is that is that
that intimacy and that trust that we
crave but i found little
bits of it online well this is exactly
what we're doing right here isn't it
brother
that's exactly what we're doing here
very close it's come it's getting there
i love where this conversation is going
especially um
like i was like i don't know what we're
gonna talk about or are we even looking
today like
that this is very game b that they what
jared touched on the monogamy
specifically that were so
focused on that creates rivalrous
dynamics
it's like you're supposed to only have
one partner historically it was of the
opposite sex
and that and yet
all of our societies is like built
around finding that person and holding
on to that person when it's only one
person
like it's like why are we dealing with
our co-workers like that you know
like like oh wait am i gonna step on
their toes in their marriage am i gonna
like
it's so concentrated around it and i
know a ton of people
who are poly and
um it's it's becoming kind of a new
thing of emerging but a lot of them are
in the closet a lot of them are like not
ready to talk about it not ready to be
open with their friends and family
and i think it is the coming thing and
that's one of the things a craigslist by
the way is horrible for online dating it
was just my weird feeling of like
putting it out to the universe and
whoever saw it it was the right one
in fact online dating gives you more of
an algorithm to base you
like to base it on something and it
breaks it because it doesn't give me
enough of an algorithm but it's like
also not just fate and randomly bumping
into each other
and that craigslist kind of felt like
and so there's something about that like
and then
it's like a job interview that you're
expected to go on a first date and
present yourself is your and then like
then the truth comes out later i'm
someone who's just like this is me
love me or hate me and but people don't
take it as that right they take it as oh
my god it's just how you're showing up
on day one
right and it's like that that kind of
comes into it as well and introverts
versus extroverts and
that that relationships have both and i
think
the lgbt community and what's coming out
of it as much as there's
some drama and issues and wokeness it
also kind of helps us break apart
what like there's there's a sex spectrum
right some people
want zero sex and people want sex all
the time there's a romance spectrum
that people like i didn't even know that
i was like oh because i knew there could
be asexuals i didn't know there could be
aromantics
and like to be able to look at that and
say here's the full spectrum and start
matching people based on that
and online dating handles polyness very
horribly where it's like you have to
like look for people as a couple
and like have one account like it's just
not designed for that it's very much
designed for like a heterosexual
monogamous
and then we'll try to tweak it if
if only it were right it's not even
designed for that i mean given the
quality of profiling algorithms that
exist today right the facebook and
google and other companies have
developed there is absolutely no reason
in the world
why dating sites with a decent database
of users could not match people up with
a very very high degree of reliability
right
but they have no incentive to do that
right they want you to be paying your 15
20 whatever dollars it is a month
and if they match you up with someone
straight away and you have really happy
well that's it they get they want and
then so the absolute opposite incentive
exists in the marketplace for them to
find you a good partner
no and it's become hookup culture and
there's nothing wrong with this
is straightforward i kind of like this
except that
everyone like that i know even people
who are totally
into hookup culture aren't like they're
like can we get something more
though right like it's just that it's
just this like surface level
getting those needs met instead of like
yeah and are we connected and
we feel like there's so much more to put
into it
that that is that is i think and that
their incentive is broken in gaming
right it doesn't pay them to get you
married until they can put you on the
picture and
showcase to find your connection and
to honor that we have this this
diversity
i feel like we've probably taken 15
minutes on this part of it
if we want to just ask jared a quick
question before we before we move on i'm
just curious about one thing with your
relationship
uh kudos by the way i mean it's it's
it's hard with the programming that we
have to let go of the jealousy and the
possessiveness and blah blah blah so
kudos for embarking on this experiment
and i
i get what you're doing and i have a lot
of admiration for i'm curious do you
interact at all with the people that
your partner is seeing like would
would you and your hook up hang out with
your girlfriend and her hookup kind of
thing is
is it that degree of openness we are
just
barely scratching the surface of this
open kind of thing for
for a little bit so at first it was um
she's queer so
we were able to bring in um females into
the relationship which to me was easier
because it was like
mentally minded
the competitive vibe of like there's
another male
here like caveman thing didn't
activate with that but um we just
so she actually just went we have an rv
now and um
we just came back from an rv trip and
she just wanted to go again and i was
like
i kind of like want like i miss my
communities of like online people and
like kind of
there's a lot of stuff i need to kind of
keep going so i stayed home
for a trip and she went to san diego and
then we started talking and there was
a another rv person that was on the road
that uh he like i guess we they
they started hitting it off and i
kind of just gave the okay mentally
and then let her know that like it was a
okay
by me and she only it was only like a
make out and she didn't really
because she got the okay like she didn't
feel the need to go further
or like it just didn't work out or
something but it was enough
for me to kind of like
taste the idea of this open relationship
and kind of
made my feet in it and it was tough like
it was definitely
like like i looked at this guy's
instagram and like was like thinking
about like
like uh yeah and like my mind just
monkey mine was just going for it but
then like i was able to override it
with my kind of like i know how much she
loves me
i know how little this will actually
mean and how
fun just the hookup can be right so
that overrode the the feeling but
um getting to a point of like if we had
consistent hookups like would we
be friends and i i guess like i would
assume so
because i think i don't know i i'll keep
you updated
we'll see how it goes i'd like to ask
you a question just because this is so
important i think
do you have a sense that
there there might be something that they
do together
that she enjoys more with him than she
does with you
all right that's the road to hell you
see you can't be having those that's
exactly the road tail
that's that's that's i wanna address
that i wanna know
well i think to me this person filled
the archetype
of everything that i was
not feeling in her life at that moment
in that specific time which was
like i would have been on the rv trip
like
doing all because she's just very much
about
this work with your hands create
something and be busy and do and it's
like
a great thing i just for me i'm more
about building an architecture in my
head
of like where we can go in the future
and like kind of this
ethereal plane where she's very much
ungrounded and so
this guy that she met has been doing van
life for like five years and like
has all like they can share this bond
whereas like we are sharing a bond and
it's it's a different bond and it's a
different thing
it's something that i i look at as a
void that that someone else can fill
there
and like have that kind of spend that
quality time enjoying that quality time
and like not
like you know kind of feeling as if
you're um appeasing the other person or
like
if i had her come on one of these calls
she would just be bored
and like she wouldn't want to have this
conversation so
um it's just we're just different we're
very different people but we find
ways that the
best parts of us link up and then we
externalize and find ways to fill
the other parts of our lives with other
people and other
you can't
do you then um get a sense of
um pleasure or satisfaction that
she's enjoying something and getting
fulfilled and and to me
that's what it took to ground it is
is my the feeling that like
i'm really just living right now i'm
just living a body in the skin of jared
right but i could be living that body in
the skin of this person too and of her
and of all these things and like
having allowing that experience to be
a fulfilled one is like really great
so if i like if i imagine myself
in their shoes then it's a great like
thing it's just like really hard to do
that so like no no no i get it i get it
that's kind of cool that you can't do
that that's good yeah yeah
transition to the next part sure because
i was going to add something to this
part but i'm like i'll add it to mine
and then i'll share
add on to that so last night i attended
the
stowa's the future thinkers foreign uv
and micron talking about their village
and they talk about how they don't have
they're not really creating rules right
they're gonna have as little rules as
possible
and i wanted to like juxtaposition that
with my community that i'm part of here
that i haven't been able to be part of
during
during the pandemic and i just had a
play date on friday with one of the
people from there
and it is a beautiful community that is
set up there are rules we create you
know it's like what is child care what
does pet care look like what does these
things look like before it was there so
there would be less conflict
but then there was there we weren't set
up for a pandemic
it's the one thing we weren't set up for
it's not designed to have social
distancing it's not designed to have
kids in and out of
or not have kids in each other's room
and the reason i'm bringing this up in
relationships
is that i think that to me that is what
my ideal
is is to not necessarily have the rules
yet
of course there's going to be rules so
constantly looking at
what are the rules i'm living by and why
is that bringing it up i know that is
partly what my queerness has helped me
do is i realized
how much i put men and women into their
boxes and treated them differently
and so when i was because it's like okay
i can't talk to this man because he's
married and she might think
that you know like i'm like wait now do
i get not get to talk to women like
let's just kind of wait a minute how
does this work i'm like i know if i'm
attracted to someone or not and i can
i can navigate that in a different way
than like the rules
are and so for me in an ideal society
i don't part of me wants to get married
because it's what i grew up with
and part of me is so far like i'm like
that sounds like the worst thing why
would i want to set myself with somebody
else for the rest of time
when we're gonna do what mark like we're
gonna grow differently and so we might
be able to plan for our pre-pandemic
time and then things change and it's
like oh wait
i want to have rv life and you want to
do this is this
what's more important to me the thing i
want or you and it's not
bad to pick one or the other but it's
like this flow in life and having people
flow into my life and out of my life
and some of that is going to be intimate
relationships that are that are
intellectual and some of them are going
to be intimate relationships that are
physical
and having that as long as there's
openness and honesty
and and as feelings are hurt as jealousy
comes up that those things are dealt
with
and i also feel like i am brave in so
many areas
but not in this one and i need
technology to help me a little bit
to for that bravery to be like okay so
in my perfect world
i would like to do um slow dating kind
of the opposite of speed dating using
the 32 questions sitting down with
someone getting to hear their full story
for an hour
not with the not with the are we matched
for forever are we monogamous pairs
but with the can i fall in love with
this human being in front of me
romantically
personally sexually doesn't matter can i
and
having it created more for introverts
where it isn't about
putting on that person it's just about i
want to be here i want to see if there's
connection
and i am um demisexual which means i
need to be
emotionally connected to someone before
i'm sexually connected before i'm
attracted to that before i want to get
it like
there's no desire until there's there's
some amount of emotion and for me
intellectual as well and so our whole
society is not set up for that it's set
up for somewhat like the people who are
who are
oh yeah no sex before marriage and this
is like this rigid structure
and the everyone like naked in five
seconds let's just like not
exchange names and it's like not set up
for
and so i would like it to just have more
diversity in
all of those spectrums and have it be
that nothing's wrong
it's just different and then how do we
how do we find your
your companionship and how do we get
intimacy in other areas and
and uh yeah i would like to hear your
beautiful futures i would just like to
say i
i i think that would be a great name for
a reality show
naked in five seconds
um so there
there is room i think for um
uh something any kind of
app or a space that builds that
community that builds
build a space where you can be
vulnerable
and people can express and witness and
and
just show how they can share in nature
and engage
right i think immediately that
that just it opens up and it uh
it shows you how you might be able to
engage that
person in in a more intimate setting
uh i i think for me if
if i could see more of that
then that would make dating a lot easier
for me
yeah i think to oh i think
you're muted there eric yes this is this
is a really tricky one i mean ordinarily
in these solution raisings i can i
can pretty clearly see what a ideal
version of the future would look like in
any given particular milieu but this is
this is a much trickier one right this
is not
this is not about designing systems or
building architectures or coming up with
plans it's not about that i mean
what turns people on what attracts
people what gets people
you know barriers to come down by the
mind this is a very
very mysterious and individual thing and
so
yeah i mean for me and this is just a
very personal thing for me
personally it would be great if our
language or
social signaling could evolve to the
point where
you could make it clear that you think
someone is
funny or sexy or interesting or whatever
without it having to be some kind of big
deal
right that there was some way of
signaling this clearly um
without any expectation of response or
whatever you know what i mean like
almost like a little
like a little neon sign that you could
program the you know
and point to the whatever you but but
somehow in our
modes of communication that such a thing
like that were to evolve that would be i
think
for me very cool
i guess going down that vein i'm my head
space is constantly in this
like what what can we do with
ai that understands human language
because that's
i'm working with a company that's doing
that right now and it's literally taking
words prepositional phrases kind of
understanding the context
of what these words mean built up so
if we had that right then what can
dating look like and to me it
seems really interesting to play with
the idea
of um you know having a really
in-depth profile that is
understood by the ai via language
and then seeing how
these different profiles interact with
each other and then gaining
patterns based off of that
and then introducing more people to
each other with some of these common
factors like maybe there's something
that they find that
that is i don't know that that creates a
synergy of some kind
yeah yeah yeah yeah some kind of thing
between the extrovert and the introvert
or there's some kind of thing that
boom boom right and then you know the
more
complete your profile is and the more
dates you go on instead of it just being
a wash or being behind a curtain that
facebook gets the access to or whatever
it is
this is actually you're doing work
towards
like your own profile that is your data
that
helps you in the system and helps you
do things in the system and you can
extrapolate that out it's not just
dating
it's finding uh a job finding work
finding people to work
books to read films to watch music to
listen to absolutely absolutely
later yeah so ever since i've kind of
learned about this
tech my head is always just going to
this place because it's so
it's such a tantalizing thing of like
what
what is possible when you have
i like to think of it as like guardian
angels on your shoulder right of like
this network of
things that understand you and can
talk to each other and then help you
get to your kind of goal so
um yeah have you guys talked about um
an algorithm that would sense
synergistic
um actions that indicate that trust is
more likely
that's interesting someone is working on
something like this i came across
something like this not very long ago in
the last couple of months i came across
something like this i can't practice
the next call remember who it is
a black mirror episode on dating i don't
know if anyone's seen it i'm going to
ruin it for you if you have
so computers that they they are
connected with people
and set up with people and you have a
first date and then
um it tells you whether compatible or
not tells you when to break up right
it's like no no you're not good
sorry hang the dj is it that episode no
i don't i never remember the names of
things and then
and then it turns that like it's
actually an ai
where they're trying to test them are
you gonna break up or are you not going
to break up and so they finally find the
person who they're willing to break the
algorithm for and that's their
connection
that's the person and there's something
there where i had it similar i know
jared we think
we think similarly and like what i want
is people to go on a first date even if
it's horrific
i'm telling what's wrong what's wrong
and right with that person they're not
right or wrong
but it's my connection to them so if i
go on a million first dates and all of
them are stupid and all of them are ugly
and
it's probably on me but like this person
they're homophobic and i don't want that
and this person's this and this person's
that
this person you know wants to live in a
big city and i want to live in a small
town
there's a quality that can emerge
with with like it it learns me but i
don't think it's so
soon we'll be switching over to the ten
thousand people and a hundred thousand
dollars
and i love that idea it's just not
doable within that
framework it's like a million dollars
but i think it's needed and there could
be a million
dollars to put towards that if people
knew it was possible right
oh you're gonna actually help me find a
mate that sounds great
with that let's we can switch over we're
already past the half an hour point
into what we could do with ten thousand
people and a hundred thousand dollars
in relationships i mean giant orgy
clearly
there are um they're not my thing what
are they called
there's a i'm sure there's a name for it
in
most cultures right and i do know the
name in jewish but i can't for the life
of me
you think what it is but the woman who
makes matches right who knows all the
families and all the parents and and and
fits people together based on intimate
knowledge of
the backgrounds and the personalities
and blah blah blah blah blah blah blah
i wonder whether something like that
could not not a technology but uh but uh
you know like within the group of 10 000
people whether
somehow or other a
i don't know i mean it's going to
require management of data isn't it
which is all done digitally these days
but
yeah something i don't know i don't know
i i don't know whether there's anything
in that but that was just something that
pops into my head
i mean i was realizing there's literally
something i could do with
a dozen people and zero dollars which is
hold a zoom meeting
for female like females or
you just can with 36 the 36 questions
and just match up and be like right this
isn't about
necessarily being the right match right
we're not
on age on anything but it's all females
who are somewhat queer right and then
just you're matched up and let's see
if there's um some kind of spark some
kind of ending and because i was trying
to do that with just
people in general and it doesn't quite
work it's like come fall in love with
another human being people didn't like
that so it didn't show up
um but having it be either just
completely open where it is all genders
all and
you're just matched with another human
being or have it for me be a little more
specific like
we're women right so having that that be
but that's like it's free show up i just
don't know how to connect people
afterwards if they do have that
connection right
because in speed dating you say yes and
if they say yes they give you they put
you in contact with each other
like that's not within my wheelhouse to
do that but um
but it would be free and just very cheap
something's coming up for me about like
how exhausting it is to go through those
30-something questions with somebody
and then be like nah you're not
like let's do it again with someone else
and it's like your soul
you're like everything is just being
like poured out
and it's wasted it's just like ah man
like
so i'm one and then like there that adds
to this fatigue of dating of like i
don't want to start this whole thing
with someone else
and like open myself up and then have
all of that just be wasted
so i'm wondering if there's a way that
like
you know you can make some kind of quest
or
game based thing
like personal game like play the jared
game or something where
it's like okay like you answer a couple
questions and then it's like you just
unlocked
like my video response to this question
because you
answered it yourself right and like you
can watch
like a five-minute thing of me
explaining what i thought about x or y
or z
right so it's as if you submit something
to somebody and then they submit
something back
and it's unlocked it's slowly unlocking
different pieces of a puzzle so you only
have to do it once
or as many times as you want but
eventually you get to the dick pic at
the end yeah
yeah exactly there you go clearly
that's that's the real goal that's what
all the heterosexual women are looking
for
but there is there is something to that
that i i love the game idea but yeah
um falling in love is is much of that
you're you're
you're making more of yourself
vulnerable and it's kind of like a
turn-taking of
sharing vulnerabilities
in that space something happens so why
why not
in the game you know where you can you
can have something like that and
it could be could be the whole community
and
you're just an avatar so you don't know
who's who until you reveal
um enough and then all of a sudden when
you reveal enough
you you get to know who that person is
and then they
um then you can you can connect so
i i could see something like that
happening i i think
in in a if if we had the right
qualifiers the right questions to ask
people
10 000 people that would join in
this is what you have to be willing to
do you know you have to be willing to be
vulnerable
you have to be willing to be
non-rivalrous
and and and nurturing in every
so if we just did it for zoom meetings a
bunch of zoom meetings
where people came in with this kind of
intention
then maybe at at the end of
20 of those you know or at the end of
five of those
um different people can indicate their
attraction for
someone else maybe you do it offline or
something but
if that would be analogous that's what i
was thinking but i like
i like that game idea too i'm not sure
which is my preference now
but i i like both of those that that
kind of mimic that
uh taking turns revealing
vulnerabilities
[Music]
funny because jared when you shared
you're like that sounds exhausting i'm
like that's what datian said like i'm
like showing up for speed dating is like
because it's so superficial
it's sitting down with somebody for an
hour i'm like perfect
the worst i did is waste an hour because
i don't think i get i don't get
exhausted by that vulnerability in the
same way
but i think there is a way i just don't
know if it breaks it to
do like record my 36 questions and then
have it yeah unlock for other people
part of the problem is it becomes that
slight swipe right and left like oh you
picked
the wrong person for your first question
so no i do not like your answer [ __ ] off
yeah because the whole point is to sit
with someone to get more and more
intimate right
so that you've also missed the back and
forth right i mean
if you previously recorded it then you
what they've responded to that question
has no influence now on your response
which it would do in an actual right you
know what i mean your response would be
very much flavored by what they've said
so yeah i'm not sure that answers to
questions like that in the abstract
necessarily work nearly as well as they
do in
real back and forth conversation i think
i think they're designed for that but
but that said i do i do really like this
notion of
gamifying it in some way are you guys
familiar with dating in the dark have
you seen this tv show
i mean this isn't even this is kind of
yeah this is gamifying dating right so
two people sit down in the pitch dark i
mean you literally can't see anything
it's black
and they sit down and they have a meal
and more often than not they really get
on very well with each other right
because you can't see each other so as
far as you're concerned you're sitting
next to your fantasy woman right because
you know there's nothing telling you to
the contrary so you can build anything
you want
but the looks of disappointment when
they see each other is so
funny they built this thing up like they
really like them you know what i mean
they built this thing
oh hi nice to meet you
[Laughter]
i do wonder if we put if we had slow
dating with the 36 questions with voice
only
not picture which kind of wrecks it the
whole point is to see them and see their
facial expressions and start but like
and then
have that like where you're not going to
be able to reject them based on looks
you might
reject them based on voice and then yes
that moment of
being open and then we all get to
experience that oh you look like that
like because it's not even like you're
not attractive necessarily it's like you
don't look like what i envisioned you to
correct
they're almost never going to be as
attractive as you picture they hope that
you they hopefully might be right almost
never
but like what if there's something where
it's like it it
means like in the same way it's kind of
like um
like quests in in games where
you are going through and somebody's
quest
is like a video a video
journey of all of these 36 questions
right
and like you can choose which ones you
want to watch you can literally
go and like once you watch 25 of the
questions
then you can like message the person or
something like you can have some
kind of unlocking thing so that if
someone watches all of your 36 questions
then they get to see who this person is
and then like
from there you can set up a zoom call or
something and then like a real life
thing it's like wow i just watched your
things like let me talk to you about
your 36 questions and like there's
something to like
the idea of two people putting in
time and effort working to get to a goal
of like would you have watched their 36
questions as well while they've been
watching yours would you have also been
watching theirs
because otherwise it's a real mystery it
would be a one-sided thing yeah
yeah i guess i guess
you i guess the way the way it would
work
would be something like somebody else
has already seen yours
you need to then now see theirs and if
you're
both interested yeah you get notified
they've seen six of your 36 questions or
something right at which point you're
right so that way there's not somebody
pining over someone else and it's like
oh you broke my heart
it's like i didn't even know who you
were
i have broken your heart like literally
yeah if you have a bunch of people that
watch
ten of yours then you're more likely to
go uh watch
theirs rather than somebody who just
watched two years right
right like there's different levels like
you see somebody watch one somebody
watched like
five and then someone watched your whole
thing and it's like all right well maybe
i'll give this person a shot i'll watch
a couple of the person who watched my
whole thing
yeah and then like oh that person's
really interesting let me just dive in
or that guy you know but maybe maybe you
literally can't even watch their whole
thing because that's
like that's that's like the first swipe
instead of a first swipe of saying yes
it's like i've watched two of your your
your
questions and like that unlocks
getting into that person's inbox so that
that person literally has to watch two
questions before more are unlocked so it
becomes oh yeah okay kind of like that
footing of back and forth and if it
doesn't go farther than that
then they don't have their heart broken
you know that kind of thing that there's
it's something there there's something
there
there's definitely something there it
needs a bit of tweaking but yeah no
there's definitely
there's definitely potential there but
this doesn't really fit the ten thousand
hundred thousand does it this is more of
a
no it could more of a morning app i mean
if you have a hundred thousand
thousand though like up front
or if you got funding for an idea
then ten thousand people would pay ten
dollars a month
to uh use this app like
the idea behind it i guess yeah i would
i would pay 10 dollars a month for this
yeah yeah and you can watch anyone's
intro video right but to what's beyond
that they then have to or
you can watch the first two or three or
one of any one video then so what's
beyond that they then have to
watch your intro video or something
before like with this
because there's the like i've i've
experienced these 36 questions with
probably about
six or seven people some men some women
and um
i changed my answers not based on who's
in front of me just based on that day
right like who would you invite to
dinner i don't have a set
one and so there's a certain amount of
that that comes into play but you can
re-record your video right so
it's it's uh that you can
be like actually that doesn't that
doesn't reflect how i feel right
now so you can no but you could also say
in your video this is what i'm saying
today but i might say something
different tomorrow right i mean that can
also be part of your video that's fair
enough or just like facebook um
so-and-so has changed their video and
you get if you're connected with that
person
all you get informed right away right
i i love the idea of
being able to connect with someone
over time like it like it's like a time
bubble
machine game so it's like i can record
these things
and it can work for a lot of different
people and
like it but it all it it like you don't
have to keep because like sometimes you
might like be with one person
and have this amazing answer and this
amazing like like
thing uh or answer to your to your
to these questions that you just want
everyone to know and see
and like then it is just gone
after that moment so i feel like having
some type of
unlockable quest
factor is is cool i think there's a
there's
something there what would it look like
then you get to save
princess and she gets to see your dick
and the more
distributed it is the more it is that
reciprocal
as opposed to everyone falling in love
with the same person right like like
this is my worry is it it re creates
that right so now i have to be
presentable in 36
questions i have to sound eloquent the
right response
like that's the opposite of what this is
but as long as
that's part of the culture that's
created it doesn't matter if some people
are like that it just matters if that
becomes the ideal that everybody has to
do
in order to get that yes right like it's
like okay well
um yeah because that's the problem of
current online dating we're looking for
reasons to say no partly because it's
rivalrous because we get one
and that was where i was like well if we
do don't do it for dating and it's more
about connection
then it doesn't like you're allowed to
fall in love with with everyone in fact
that was kind of the point where like if
you sit with someone
you've sat with 10 people and you've
realized they're all have something that
you love about them
extrapolate that to humanity because
that was the point it's like
whereas if you're looking if you're here
to find the one
then yes anyone who's not that person is
disappointing
right it's like oh no no no as opposed
to what can i find here
what do you have that is
that game could also indicate that um
how comfortable
you are like you could be it could
indicate poly people as well
and and people who are interested in
some
other level of intimacy or just
a complementary type of relationships uh
it could could indicate all of that
and so and it would be better for you if
if you were as
true about your weirdness and your kinks
because
that that would get so you know you make
that clear
yeah some people need that to be video
one and some people need that to be
video 50
like which is i was just thinking though
for especially for poly people
on current apps where they have to as a
couple go out and look for people
which is always just weird it's weird in
general but in this case
even if you are the person who's okay
dating a couple and that's what they're
looking for
you actually have to like both you know
what i mean like it's like you have to
like this person and this person
and it's not and in a way where you
don't even necessarily know they're tied
you know that they're in a relationship
because that's part of the information
but you don't know they're in a
relationship with each other and then
you might get that information like
oh jared they liked your partner but not
you is she okay though like
or vice versa or you find the person
who's actually
is oh wow connected to both of you
but that could be unlocked on the way
down like a 12th question or something
you learn this thing then you have you
you and only you
who've been led into that level have
that information
and you know they reciprocally have that
information on you so that
that's kind of like a cool thing too and
because you you both can look at that
that same person at the same time and
what i also really like about this
like video diary kind of quest
idea is that you are
able to be your most true self
without like like you you have
the you don't have the pressure of if
you're with someone
saying something that like oh maybe
because they said this
i'm now gonna say this versus what you
were going to say
which might have been like nerdier or
more like weird or whatever and like
those like you actually have the freedom
to be weird and do those weird things
and then
know that like the the game
is like playing itself like there are
they're going to be
like you don't need to like to to
to be so um
what's the word you don't need to be in
the room with the person that thinks
you're a weirdo they can just move on to
the next video yeah and like you don't
need to you don't
to you need to curate all your reactions
curated
yeah you you are less
oh man there's a word for it this is
killing me
um let attached i guess
less attached to your uh your answers
and like knowing that you can
be like a weirder
version of yourself and like the truer
version yourself and eventually
someone will find that and say wow
that's that's a person i really want to
get to know you know
yeah that's a wonderful reward really
great
your true weird self and be accepted and
that person has come down the chain
and has accepted and fought their way
through you right yeah
there are some of these questions it
always annoys me when i'm sitting with
the person because i hate these ones
the question is it asks it three
different times i believe in each set of
questions
what do you and your partner have in
common um which is funny because the
last person i did this with he
he actually is a polly anyway he
answered it for his white like for his
wife and said i'm like you know we are
partners
oh okay it's like well she's real i'm
like
that's not me you're not describing me
but anyway it was kind of funny but like
that you're asking what do we have in
common and it's it's increasing but that
could be something that is actually
typed in right
after i've seen five year videos what do
we have in common okay
well we both like anime or we might
whatever right like that is
this is what i liked about this person
and getting that feedback from somebody
right not because you're
trying to but i think that we try to be
someone to be palatable to the masses
instead of being our unique self right
because it is very broadcast instead of
interconnected so if you can get
feedback on like oh i love that you were
like this court it's your quirkiness
it's going to draw people in all honesty
and so what someone sees in you writing
those things down and getting that is
like
oh they liked that i'm weird i love it
and it starts to reinforce that
and you get to be you're weird because
you can be weird in an infinite number
of ways
whereas you can kind of only be normal
in one way so
it's like all the weirdness that we like
and yet we're trying to be normal so
that people feel like it's that weird
it doesn't do it you get to be you hey
that could be the name of the app
get to be you nice you get to be you
nice there's something there i think
that's cool
i'm glad this is recorded because we can
kind of like look back on this or
this also is something interesting in
that
we could if someone was interested in
the idea
in the future when we're pitching this
or whatever like oh here you can
actually
see how this came about and maybe this
can spark inspiration
watch this video it's like oh okay i'm
caught up now i know i
it's like there's there's that aspect i
love playing with of like
recording these gems over time
so that you don't have to keep doing
something
and but like it can like build from
where you left off you know and like
like oh i i know what you're talking
about
here's this other thing that i want to
add because blank blank blank blank you
know
um i think it's cool
i'm i'm excited for the idea of other
people having solution raising so
there's parallel ones and seeing what
multiple conversations come with up with
are they different are they the same
just based on who's around the table
yeah um and so part of my vision was
that like there would be a
topic of the week and everyone all over
the world would be having that same
conversation
but that's there's also the absolutely
unsynchronous right
when you were having the relationship
question today but some other group is
having it in six months but it's
compiled in the same
place right right so but do you i don't
what i don't want but it's okay people
is that for people to watch
hours before they have theirs right
because i actually want them
to come to it with a fresh hey i don't
want to think what that is but
it also doesn't break it if they do
right they come and they're like
[ __ ] remember what jared said in the
first solution i've seen that
right this is exactly what kylie's up to
right this is i mean this is exactly
what kylie is trying to create is
is that kind of platform
for getting then you know that one thing
she sent
out right this is exactly what she's
trying to do is create an ecology
for the sense-making milieu
so that um people know what's going on
when it's going on
what time zone it's in you can search by
timezone you can search by present you
can search by theme you can search by
topic whatever yeah i remember that um
and uh yeah and and
i mean again it's a big giant complex
thing and kylie
seems to be able to hold all of this
[ __ ] in some
i don't know how she does it because she
can't sort of
it's not in a way that she can break
down and explain right but she but she
does somehow
hold it all um so yeah but she has she
has matched it out she has maxed out i
mean
did you say kill yourself did you say
kylie
i don't think i've met her no i don't
think i mean we we know her from a
call that we have on wednesdays um but
she's
yeah she's not she would come to these
except their horrible timing for
australia
yeah it's like three in the morning i
almost want to like have a different one
at a different time
basically just so she can come just and
the other but when we did that with
together tech
but yeah the idea of coordinating
solution ratings right so solution
rating is held on dating today right and
then in six months time another one is
held these two would somehow be
linked together because they they'd have
the same tags on them and so they would
then
form a linked group of things discussing
the same
thing but which occurred at different
times right so people come along later
can see
the whole body of relevant stuff that's
going on i mean that's
that's that's exactly what she's seeking
to do is put it all together in that
kind of
meaningful useful intuitive navigable
sort of way
how would she go about getting the
knowledge
out of the videos or out of the
meetings like is she going through and
doing this by hand or
no no no no i mean she's not she's not
it's her job is not to transcribe
everything that gets put up there and
then and then condense it down into five
minutes of useful notes no i mean if
people want to do that
then they can do so and then it goes no
she wants to create a sort of
um a framework an ecology a platform
where um so you know when john vivacy is
going to be giving a talk on
whatever right and you can find that
really easily you can find it by john
vivek you can find it by meaning crisis
by date and time and time zone whatever
um and so it's about tagging all of
these things in such ways that they can
be
easily found and easily linked together
um
and it's also about matching me you know
so i don't know there's there's an event
going on which has a capacity of 50
people but 300 people want to do it then
that somehow goes back to the event
organizer so they can expand it or put
on more dates or whatever
and so there's a there's a way of need
and capacity being
matched with each other also in this
um so we're past the hour but we start a
little late i just want to
um this is my attempt to do an hour and
five minutes so that if somebody only
wants to watch the end they only have to
watch the end to get what we did
is what do you think is the most
powerful solution for relationships and
dating that we could do with ten
thousand people and a hundred thousand
dollars that you would like to see
either something we talked about or
something that comes up in the moment
well i i definitely want something that
um builds that space for trust and
vulnerability and um the
it's i think the the thing that we kind
of
co-created at the end seems like it
could do that for me like if
if we had that community where you have
either questions or some
incremental revealing of vulnerabilities
and that
everybody else could be aware of i'd
like to see that take place that that
for me
seems like something we could actually
do
i like that phrase incremental reveal
incremental revealing that's exactly
what it is it's very good it's a nice
phrase
this was a unique one that we kind of
did um combine something together where
it just builds on instead of like or
take it this way
and so yeah what we have here at the end
is very powerful something that is more
intimate questions whether it's those 36
that is gamified that is unlocking that
is
also if it's something we come together
which we didn't really talk about
it's also something we can improve on
all of my worries of like well what if
it turns into a meat market too
is like right but if we're there and
we're there for the purpose of
relationships that's different than
being there for the purpose of that ten
dollars a month right
the ten dollars is to get us
relationships not the other way around
yeah i that's
spot on i mean i i'm i'm like
going in my head of like what are the
next steps to get a deck together for
something like this so we can pass
around because that's like i think it's
a really cool idea that i haven't seen
yet
and i think that with the right
connections and like you can get funding
for something like that pretty easily i
think if there is
somebody that sees that and says oh yeah
like i would love that in my life like
boom there you go so um
maybe that'll be my my homework is to to
come next week with a
rough deck that we can all kind of mock
up but i would love that
yeah awesome all right goodbye to
youtube